Speier, Hans; Papers ger084
M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections & Archives
- Manuscripts and typescripts, ca. 1920-1987; 4
  - Typescripts and manuscripts of early unpublished poems and short stories, published and unpublished essayistic writings, 1920-1987; 4.2; 160 file folders
    - Essayistic writings, arranged chronologically, Undated; 4.2.3
      - "What Hitler Might Say on November 8", 1943; typescript (Box 8 (4.2.3-Essayistic writings, arranged chronologically), Folder 6)
      - "Information gleaned from German Documents", 1944 December 5; typescript (Box 8 (4.2.3-Essayistic writings, arranged chronologically), Folder 7)
      - "Special Guidance on German Military Exit Propaganda", 1945 May 19; typescript (Box 8 (4.2.3-Essayistic writings, arranged chronologically), Folder 8)
      - Propaganda directives, 1945-1946 (Box 8 (4.2.3-Essayistic writings, arranged chronologically), Folder 9)
      - "War Aims in Political Warfare", 1946 May; reprint (Box 8 (4.2.3-Essayistic writings, arranged chronologically), Folder 10)
      - "Immediate and Future Responsibilities of the Department of State for the Reeducation of Germany", 1946 May 26; typescript (Box 8 (4.2.3-Essayistic writings, arranged chronologically), Folder 11)
      - "Ernst Juenger", 1947; typescript (Box 8 (4.2.3-Essayistic writings, arranged chronologically), Folder 12)
      - Short texts, 1947-1948 (Box 8 (4.2.3-Essayistic writings, arranged chronologically), Folder 13)
      - "The Future of German Nationalism", 1947 December; reprint (Box 8 (4.2.3-Essayistic writings, arranged chronologically), Folder 14)
      - "Goebbels: Das Reich". Translations, undated; typescript (Box 8 (4.2.3-Essayistic writings, arranged chronologically), Folder 15)
      - "The Future of Psychological Warfare", Spring 1948; reprint (Box 8 (4.2.3-Essayistic writings, arranged chronologically), Folder 16)
      - "Historical Development of Public Opinion", 1950 January; reprint (Box 8 (4.2.3-Essayistic writings, arranged chronologically), Folder 17)
      - Transcript of talk on National Security and Federal Employees, 1952; typescript (Box 8 (4.2.3-Essayistic writings, arranged chronologically), Folder 18)
      - "Truth and Stratagem in Political Speech", 1952 March 10; typescript (Box 8 (4.2.3-Essayistic writings, arranged chronologically), Folder 19)
      - "Research in International Communication: An Advisory Report", 1953; bound typescript (Box 8 (4.2.3-Essayistic writings, arranged chronologically), Folder 20)
      - "Differential Discourse", 1954 January; typescript (Box 8 (4.2.3-Essayistic writings, arranged chronologically), Folder 21)
      - "Germany's Reluctant Rearmament". Advertisement of talk by Speier, 1955 February 23 (Box 8 (4.2.3-Essayistic writings, arranged chronologically), Folder 22)
      - "War and Peace", 1955 November; reprint (Box 8 (4.2.3-Essayistic writings, arranged chronologically), Folder 23)
      - "Die Intellektuellen im Exil", undated; typescript (Box 8 (4.2.3-Essayistic writings, arranged chronologically), Folder 24)
      - "Political Games and Scenarios", 1961 May 6; typescript (Box 8 (4.2.3-Essayistic writings, arranged chronologically), Folder 25)
      - "Die Abenteurerin Courasche", 1964; typescript (Box 8 (4.2.3-Essayistic writings, arranged chronologically), Folder 26)
      - "Grimmelshausens Gelächter", 1964; typescript (Box 8 (4.2.3-Essayistic writings, arranged chronologically), Folder 27)
      - "Simplicissimus, the Irreverent Fool", Spring 1966; reprint (Box 8 (4.2.3-Essayistic writings, arranged chronologically), Folder 28)
      - "Simplicissimus, der Mann ohne Ehrfurcht", 1966; typescript (Box 8 (4.2.3-Essayistic writings, arranged chronologically), Folder 29)
      - Grimmelshausen translations, ca. 1966 (Box 8 (4.2.3-Essayistic writings, arranged chronologically), Folder 30)
      - "Fällen des politischen Humors", 1966 October; typescript (Box 8 (4.2.3-Essayistic writings, arranged chronologically), Folder 31)
      - "H. Speier Talk, 2-14-67" (Box 8 (4.2.3-Essayistic writings, arranged chronologically), Folder 32)
      - "Hof und Schenke im Deutschen Barockroman", 1968; typescript (Box 8 (4.2.3-Essayistic writings, arranged chronologically), Folder 33)
      - "Der Narr und die Gesellschaftsordnung", 1969; typescript (Box 8 (4.2.3-Essayistic writings, arranged chronologically), Folder 34)
      - "H. Speier Talk, 4-10-69" (Box 8 (4.2.3-Essayistic writings, arranged chronologically), Folder 35)
      - "Divided Germany in World Affairs", undated; typescript (Box 8 (4.2.3-Essayistic writings, arranged chronologically), Folder 36)
      - "Europa aus amerikanischer Sicht", 1969 April; clipping (Box 8 (4.2.3-Essayistic writings, arranged chronologically), Folder 37)
      - "Limited Peace", Winter 1969; reprint (Box 8 (4.2.3-Essayistic writings, arranged chronologically), Folder 38)
      - "The Rise of Public Opinion", 1969; typescript (Box 8 (4.2.3-Essayistic writings, arranged chronologically), Folder 39)
      - Outlines for planned essay volumes, ca. 1970-1972 (Box 8 (4.2.3-Essayistic writings, arranged chronologically), Folder 40)
      - "Karl Mannheim als Wissenssoziologe", 1970; typescripts (Box 8 (4.2.3-Essayistic writings, arranged chronologically), Folder 41)
      - "Karl Mannheim as a Sociologist of Knowledge", after 1973; typescript (Box 8 (4.2.3-Essayistic writings, arranged chronologically), Folder 42)
      - "Über den politischen Witz", 1972 June; typescripts, reprint (Box 8 (4.2.3-Essayistic writings, arranged chronologically), Folder 43)
      - "Der politische Witz", 1972; typescripts (Box 8 (4.2.3-Essayistic writings, arranged chronologically), Folder 44)
      - "On Humor and Political Wit", 1972; typescripts (Box 8 (4.2.3-Essayistic writings, arranged chronologically), Folder 45-46)
      - "The Chances for Peace", 1974 June 20-1974 June 21 (Box 8 (4.2.3-Essayistic writings, arranged chronologically), Folder 47)
        Typescript, panel discussion.
      - "The Chances for Peace", Spring 1975; typescript, reprint (Box 8 (4.2.3-Essayistic writings, arranged chronologically), Folder 48)
      - "Détente", ca. 1975; typescript (Box 8 (4.2.3-Essayistic writings, arranged chronologically), Folder 49)
      - "Begegnung mit einem jungen Maler im Nachkriegsdeutschland", 1977; reprint (Box 8 (4.2.3-Essayistic writings, arranged chronologically), Folder 50)
      - Speech notes, New School for Social Research, 1977 May 20 (Box 8 (4.2.3-Essayistic writings, arranged chronologically), Folder 51)
      - "The Communication of Hidden Meaning", 1977; typescripts (Box 8 (4.2.3-Essayistic writings, arranged chronologically), Folder 52-54)
      - "The Communication of Hidden Meaning", Autumn 1977; reprint (Box 8 (4.2.3-Essayistic writings, arranged chronologically), Folder 55)
      - "The Truth in Hell: Maurice Joly on Modern Despotism", Fall 1977; typescripts, reprint (Box 8 (4.2.3-Essayistic writings, arranged chronologically), Folder 56)
      - "Columbia Lecture: Historians. Frankfurt vs. New School", after 1980; typescript (Box 8 (4.2.3-Essayistic writings, arranged chronologically), Folder 57)
      - "Remarks by Hans Speier. New School Convocation, Berlin, December 7, 1984", typescript (Box 8 (4.2.3-Essayistic writings, arranged chronologically), Folder 58)
      - "Wit and Politics: An Essay on Laughter and Power", 1998 March; reprint (Box 8 (4.2.3-Essayistic writings, arranged chronologically), Folder 59)
      - Miscellaneous unidentified typescripts (Box 8 (4.2.3-Essayistic writings, arranged chronologically), Folder 60)
    - Books reviewed by Hans Speier, Undated; 4.2.4 (Box 8 (4-Manuscripts and typescripts), Folder 61-80)
      - N. Bucharin Die politische Oekonomie des Rentners, 1928; reprint (Box 8 (4.2.4-Books reviewed by Hans Speier), Folder 61)
      - Paul Kampffmeyer and Dr. Bruno Altmann Vor dem Sozialistengesetz, 1928; reprint (Box 8 (4.2.4-Books reviewed by Hans Speier), Folder 62)
      - Gustav Mayer Bismarck und Lassalle. Ihr Briefwechsel und ihre Gespräche, 1928; reprint (Box 8 (4.2.4-Books reviewed by Hans Speier), Folder 63)
      - Die neue Jugend. Forschungen zur Völkerpsychologie und Soziologie, 1928 October; reprint (Box 8 (4.2.4-Books reviewed by Hans Speier), Folder 64)
      - Theodor Geiger Die Gestalten der Gesellung. Page proof, 1929 April (Box 8 (4.2.4-Books reviewed by Hans Speier), Folder 65)
      - Ernst Barnikol, D as entdeckte Christentum im Vormärz; Weitling, der Gefangene und seine "Gerechtigkeit"; Wilhelm Weitling, Gerechtigkeit. Ein Studium in 500 Tagen, 1930 January; reprint (Box 8 (4.2.4-Books reviewed by Hans Speier), Folder 66)
      - Otto Gmelin Naturgeschichte des Bürgers, 1930 March; reprint (Box 8 (4.2.4-Books reviewed by Hans Speier), Folder 67)
      - Ferdinand Tönnies Der Kampf um das Sozialistengesetz. Page proof, 1930 August (Box 8 (4.2.4-Books reviewed by Hans Speier), Folder 68)
      - Hans Prinzhorn, "Zur Psychologie der Sozialversicherten", 1931; mimeographed typescript (Box 8 (4.2.4-Books reviewed by Hans Speier), Folder 69)
      - Hans Freyer. Soziologie als Wirklichkeitswissenschaft, 1931 August-1931 September; reprint (Box 8 (4.2.4-Books reviewed by Hans Speier), Folder 70)
      - Friedrich Gogarten Politische Ethik; Sigmund Neumann, Die deutsche Parteien; Ernst Jünger, Der Arbeiter; Robert Dinse, Das Freizeitleben der Großstadtjugend, 1932; reprint (Box 8 (4.2.4-Books reviewed by Hans Speier), Folder 71)
      - Ferdinand Tönnies.Einführung in die Soziologie; Max Horkheimer. Anfänge der bürgerlichen Geschichtsphilosophie, 1932 November; reprint (Box 8 (4.2.4-Books reviewed by Hans Speier), Folder 72)
      - Karl Marx/Friedrich Engels Historisch-kritische Gesamtausgabe, 1932 December; reprint (Box 8 (4.2.4-Books reviewed by Hans Speier), Folder 73)
      - Carl Schmitt Der Begriff des Politischen, 1932; typescript (Box 8 (4.2.4-Books reviewed by Hans Speier), Folder 74)
      - W. I. Lenin Ausgewählte Werke in 12 Bänden; Kurt Sauerland, Der dialektische Materialismus, 1933 February; reprint (Box 8 (4.2.4-Books reviewed by Hans Speier), Folder 75)
      - Handwörterbuch der Soziologie, 1933 February; reprint (Box 8 (4.2.4-Books reviewed by Hans Speier), Folder 76)
      - Enquête sur les conditions de vie de chômeurs assurés, 1933 August-1933 September; reprint (Box 8 (4.2.4-Books reviewed by Hans Speier), Folder 77)
      - Max Horkheimer Studien über Autorität und Familie, 1936 November; reprint (Box 8 (4.2.4-Books reviewed by Hans Speier), Folder 78)
      - The Goebbels Diaries 1942-1943, ed. Louis P. Lochner, Fall 1948; reprint (Box 8 (4.2.4-Books reviewed by Hans Speier), Folder 79)
      - Carl J. Friedrich Totalitarian Dictatorship and Autocracy, 1956; typescript (Box 8 (4.2.4-Books reviewed by Hans Speier), Folder 80)
    - John W. Masland and Laurence I. Radway Soldiers and Scholars: Military Education and National Policy, 1958; clipping (Box 8 (4-Manuscripts and typescripts), Folder 81)
    - Morris Janowitz The Professional Soldier: A Social and Political Portrait, 1960; clipping (Box 8 (4-Manuscripts and typescripts), Folder 82)
    - Oran R. Young The Politics of Force, 1968; typescript (Box 8 (4-Manuscripts and typescripts), Folder 83)
    - "Review of Jaspers: The Future of Germany", 1968 December; reprints (Box 8 (4-Manuscripts and typescripts), Folder 84)
    - Hsi-Huey Lang The Berlin Police Force in the Weimar Republic, 1971 March; reprint (Box 8 (4-Manuscripts and typescripts), Folder 85)
    - S. N. Eisenstadt Political Sociology: A Reader, 1972; clipping (Box 8 (4-Manuscripts and typescripts), Folder 86)
    - Detlev Grieswelle Propaganda der Friedlosigkeit, 1972; typescript (Box 8 (4-Manuscripts and typescripts), Folder 87)
    - Martin Jay The Dialectical Imagination: A History of the Frankfurt School and the Institute of Social Research, 1923-1950, 1976 December; typescript, reprint (Box 8 (4-Manuscripts and typescripts), Folder 88)
    - Jürgen Kocka Angestellte zwischen Faschismus und Demokratie, 1977; typescript (Box 8 (4-Manuscripts and typescripts), Folder 89)
    - E. V. Walter, Vytautas Kavolis, Edmund Leites, and Marie Coleman Nelson The Civilization Perspective, 1981; typescript (Box 8 (4-Manuscripts and typescripts), Folder 90)
    - Kendall L. Baker, Russel J. Dalton and Kai Hildebrand Germany Transformed -- Political Culture and the New Politics, 1982 May; clipping (Box 8 (4-Manuscripts and typescripts), Folder 91)
    - Dirk Käsler Soziologische Abenteuer, 1987; typescript (Box 8 (4-Manuscripts and typescripts), Folder 92)
- The RAND Corporation materials, 1948-1988; 5; 130 file folders
  This series consists of log notes generated by Speier while on trips for The RAND Corporation of Santa Monica, California, as well as essays, position papers and memoranda generated by Speier (and others) while in the employ of The RAND Corporation.
  Arranged in two sub-series.
  - Log notes, 1952-1955; 1962; 1968; 5.1; 16 file folders
    This series contains Speier's log (diary) notes from trips to Germany taken for The RAND Corporation, the people he met and interviewed, places visited, etc. Sections of the log notes served as a basis for his autobiography From the Ashes of Disgrace: A Journal from Germany 1945-1955.
    - Log notes, numbered 1-30, 1952 April 19-1952 May 13 (Box 9 (5-The RAND Corporation materials), Folder 1)
    - Log notes, numbered 31-35, 37, 39-41, 15-24 May 1952 (Box 9 (5-The RAND Corporation materials), Folder 2)
    - "Arbeitstagung am 24. Mai [1952] in Frankfurt mit Mr. Speier", Undated (Box 9 (5-The RAND Corporation materials), Folder 3)
    - Log notes, numbered 42-48, 50-58, 60, 1952 May 25-1952 June 17 (Box 9 (5-The RAND Corporation materials), Folder 4)
    - Log notes, numbered 1-10, 1954 March 27-1954 April 8 (Box 9 (5-The RAND Corporation materials), Folder 5)
    - Log notes, numbered 11-25, 1954 April 11-1954 May 3 (Box 9 (5-The RAND Corporation materials), Folder 6)
    - Log notes, numbered 26-38, 1954 May 5-1954 May 16 (Box 9 (5-The RAND Corporation materials), Folder 7)
    - Log notes, numbered 39-49, 1954 May 17-1954 June 1 (Box 9 (5-The RAND Corporation materials), Folder 8)
    - Log notes, numbered 1-49, incomplete, 1954 March 27-1954 June 1 (Box 9 (5-The RAND Corporation materials), Folder 9-10)
    - Log notes, numbered 1-15, 1955 September-1955 October (Box 9 (5-The RAND Corporation materials), Folder 11-12)
    - Log notes, numbered 1-15, incomplete, 1955 September-1955 October (Box 9 (5-The RAND Corporation materials), Folder 13-14)
    - Notes on trip to Europe, 1962 September-1962 October (Box 9 (5-The RAND Corporation materials), Folder 15)
    - Trip report, 1968 February 8-24 (Box 9 (5-The RAND Corporation materials), Folder 16)
  - Essays, position papers, memoranda, 1948-1988; 5.2; 114 file folders
    Although this series contains primarily memoranda and essays generated for The RAND Corporation by Hans Speier or under his direction, general materials and correspondence pertaining to RAND, as well as some essays by others are also included in this series.
    - RAND Corporation correspondence, 1948-1988 (Box 9 (5-The RAND Corporation materials), Folder 17)
    - RAND memoranda, 1948-1949 (Box 9 (5-The RAND Corporation materials), Folder 18)
      (generated by individuals other than H. Speier).
    - RAND memoranda, 1950-1959 (Box 9 (5-The RAND Corporation materials), Folder 19)
    - Bibliography of [Speier] RAND Publications, 1949-1959 (Box 9 (5-The RAND Corporation materials), Folder 20)
      Note cards, partial listing.
    - Selected RAND Abstracts, 1987 (Box 9 (5-The RAND Corporation materials), Folder 21)
    - Miscellaneous RAND materials, Undated (Box 9 (5-The RAND Corporation materials), Folder 22)
    - Essays, memoranda, position papers authored by or prepared under the direction of Hans Speier, Undated; 5.2.7
      - "A Prospective Division for International Studies", 1948 February 12; mimeograph (Box 9 (5.2.7-Essays, memoranda, position papers authored by or ), Folder 23)
      - "Description of German Propaganda Directives", 1948 August 31; mimeograph (Box 9 (5.2.7-Essays, memoranda, position papers authored by or ), Folder 24)
      - "Note on Time Perspective", 1948 September 13; typescript, notes (Box 9 (5.2.7-Essays, memoranda, position papers authored by or ), Folder 25)
      - "Note: Hypotheses Regarding War and Violence (U.S. Elite)", 1948 September 13; mimeograph (Box 9 (5.2.7-Essays, memoranda, position papers authored by or ), Folder 26)
      - "Note on Foreign vs. Domestic Policy", 1948 September 13; mimeograph (Box 9 (5.2.7-Essays, memoranda, position papers authored by or ), Folder 27)
      - "Soviet View of Diplomacy", 1949 March 1-1949 March 7; typescript (Box 9 (5.2.7-Essays, memoranda, position papers authored by or ), Folder 28)
      - "Hoover Commission on public opinion and propaganda", 1949 June 1; mimeograph (Box 9 (5.2.7-Essays, memoranda, position papers authored by or ), Folder 29)
      - "Summary of Instructions for Control of the Czech Press", 1949 September 25; typescript (Box 9 (5.2.7-Essays, memoranda, position papers authored by or ), Folder 30)
      - "Notes on German Nationalism", 1949 September; typescript (Box 9 (5.2.7-Essays, memoranda, position papers authored by or ), Folder 31)
      - "Comments on Current Policy Requirements", 1949 November 21; typescript (Box 9 (5.2.7-Essays, memoranda, position papers authored by or ), Folder 32)
      - "Discussion of Professor Blumer's Paper", 1949 December 29; typescript (Box 9 (5.2.7-Essays, memoranda, position papers authored by or ), Folder 33)
      - "The Role of Information Media in the Public Affairs Program for Germany: A Reassessment", 1950; typescript (Box 9 (5.2.7-Essays, memoranda, position papers authored by or ), Folder 34)
      - "Propaganda and Its Setting. Address, April 10, 1950, at the Foreign Service Institute", typescript, pamphlet (Box 9 (5.2.7-Essays, memoranda, position papers authored by or ), Folder 35)
      - "Psychological Warfare Reconsidered."Pamphlet. Washington, D.C.: Department of State, Foreign Service Institute, 1951 (Box 9 (5.2.7-Essays, memoranda, position papers authored by or ), Folder 36)
      - "A Policy for Ending Soviet Aggression", 1951 January 12; typescript (Box 9 (5.2.7-Essays, memoranda, position papers authored by or ), Folder 37)
      - "Psychoanalysis and Sociological Interpretation", 1951 February 9; typescript (Box 9 (5.2.7-Essays, memoranda, position papers authored by or ), Folder 38)
      - "Germany's Unification", 1951 January-1951 March; typescript (Box 9 (5.2.7-Essays, memoranda, position papers authored by or ), Folder 39)
      - Memorandum on General Halder's Diary, 1951 May 25; mimeograph (Box 9 (5.2.7-Essays, memoranda, position papers authored by or ), Folder 40)
      - "Conversation with General Norstad (H.S. & W.P.D.)", 1951 November 19 (Box 9 (5.2.7-Essays, memoranda, position papers authored by or ), Folder 41)
        Typescript. Fontainebleau.
      - "Psychological Vulnerability of the Soviet and Satellite States", 1951 November 27 (Box 9 (5.2.7-Essays, memoranda, position papers authored by or ), Folder 42)
        Typescript. Heidelberg.
      - Comments on the research problem on National Security and Freedom of Thought, 1951 December; typescript (Box 9 (5.2.7-Essays, memoranda, position papers authored by or ), Folder 43)
      - "Notes on Interviews with Former German Officers", 1951; typescript (Box 9 (5.2.7-Essays, memoranda, position papers authored by or ), Folder 44)
      - "Notes on German Veterans Organizations", 1951 December 12; typescript (Box 9 (5.2.7-Essays, memoranda, position papers authored by or ), Folder 45)
      - Short texts, 1952 (Box 9 (5.2.7-Essays, memoranda, position papers authored by or ), Folder 46)
      - "Psychological and Political Strategy", 1952 February 11; typescript (Box 9 (5.2.7-Essays, memoranda, position papers authored by or ), Folder 47)
      - "Truth and Stratagem in Political Speech", 1952 March 10; typescript (Box 9 (5.2.7-Essays, memoranda, position papers authored by or ), Folder 48)
      - "International Political Communication: Elite vs. Mass", 1952 April; reprint (Box 9 (5.2.7-Essays, memoranda, position papers authored by or ), Folder 49)
      - Comments on Bernard Brodie's "The Heritage of Douhet", 1952 October 28; typescript (Box 9 (5.2.7-Essays, memoranda, position papers authored by or ), Folder 50)
      - "Memorandum on RAND Organization and Management", 1952 October 31; typescript (Box 9 (5.2.7-Essays, memoranda, position papers authored by or ), Folder 51)
      - Comments on Nathan Leites' "The Politburo Speaks", 1952 November 6; typescript (Box 9 (5.2.7-Essays, memoranda, position papers authored by or ), Folder 52)
      - Letter to Prof. Leo Strauss, 1952 November 12 (Box 9 (5.2.7-Essays, memoranda, position papers authored by or ), Folder 53)
      - "Soviet Cold War Campaigns", 1952 December 3; mimeograph (Box 9 (5.2.7-Essays, memoranda, position papers authored by or ), Folder 54)
      - Short texts, 1953 (Box 9 (5.2.7-Essays, memoranda, position papers authored by or ), Folder 55)
      - "Comments on 'A Year End Survey of Rightest and Nationalist Sentiments in West Germany'", 1953 January 30; bound mimeograph (Box 9 (5.2.7-Essays, memoranda, position papers authored by or ), Folder 56)
      - Letter to Nathan Leites, 1953 March 6 (Box 9 (5.2.7-Essays, memoranda, position papers authored by or ), Folder 57)
      - Notes by H. Speier and Aaron Bell on Misrepresentation, 1953; typescripts (Box 9 (5.2.7-Essays, memoranda, position papers authored by or ), Folder 58)
      - "German Opinions on German Rearmament". Vol. 1, 1953 July 15; bound mimeograph (Box 9 (5.2.7-Essays, memoranda, position papers authored by or ), Folder 59)
      - "German Opinions on German Rearmament". Vol. 2, 1953 July 15; bound mimeograph (Box 9 (5.2.7-Essays, memoranda, position papers authored by or ), Folder 60)
      - "Foreign Policy and International Communication", 1953 September 10-1953 September 12; mimeograph (Box 9 (5.2.7-Essays, memoranda, position papers authored by or ), Folder 61)
      - "Some Cases of Successful Political Warfare", 1953 September 23; typescript (Box 9 (5.2.7-Essays, memoranda, position papers authored by or ), Folder 62)
      - "German Rearmament and the Old Military Elite", 1954 January; reprint (Box 9 (5.2.7-Essays, memoranda, position papers authored by or ), Folder 63)
      - "Notes of the Discussion on Privacy Held with Hans, April 30, 1955", typescript (Box 9 (5.2.7-Essays, memoranda, position papers authored by or ), Folder 64)
      - "Notes on German Rearmament", 1955 May 13; mimeograph (Box 9 (5.2.7-Essays, memoranda, position papers authored by or ), Folder 65)
      - "War and Peace", 1955 November; reprint (Box 9 (5.2.7-Essays, memoranda, position papers authored by or ), Folder 66)
      - "Trip to Germany by E. W. Schnitzer and Hans Speier", 1955 December 7; mimeograph (Box 10 (5.2.7-Essays, memoranda, position papers authored by or ), Folder 1)
      - "Excerpts from Briefing delivered to Washington Staff by Hans Speier, Friday, Dec. 9, 1955", typescript (Box 10 (5.2.7-Essays, memoranda, position papers authored by or ), Folder 2)
      - "Notes on Non-Verbal Language in Politics", 1956 January 23; typescript (Box 10 (5.2.7-Essays, memoranda, position papers authored by or ), Folder 3)
      - "Statement of Interests", 1956 March 22; typescript (Box 10 (5.2.7-Essays, memoranda, position papers authored by or ), Folder 4)
      - "Soviet Atomic Blackmail and the North Atlantic Alliance", 1957 April; reprint (Box 10 (5.2.7-Essays, memoranda, position papers authored by or ), Folder 5)
      - "Limited War", 1957 November 27; typescript and mimeograph (Box 10 (5.2.7-Essays, memoranda, position papers authored by or ), Folder 6)